Guide to the G. & C. Merriam Company Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Historical File, 1804-1977; Series I; 10.8; (26 boxes)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Collins Dictionary, 1877 Mar 19 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Cook, Edward, 1876-78 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Cook, Increase, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 76)
      Letter to John Babcock & Co. dated Feb 12 1803 is a photocopy
    - Coolidge, George F., 1866, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Cox, Rowland (Box 8, Folder 78)
      Typescript carbons of letter from Cox to Merriam Co. dated Nov 10 1894 and response of Merriam Co. to Cox dated Nov 12 1894
    - Cox, Walter S., 1882-90 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Craig, J. P., 1856 Jul 9 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Curtis, Benjamin Robbins, 1860-64 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Curtis, George William, 1856-64 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Cushing, Caleb, 1850-81 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - "D" general, 1854-59 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - D. Appleton & Co., 1855-66 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Dana, Edward Salisbury, 1889 Apr (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Dana, Henry S., 1860 Jun-Jul (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Davidson, David, 1850 Jun 14 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Dawson, R., 1889 Dec 29 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Depew, Chauncey M., 1890 Dec 5 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Dexter, Franklin Bowditch, 1878-1908 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Draper, Lyman C., 1858 Apr 15 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Dwight, Theodore, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1889 Sep 24 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - "E" general, 1850-80, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 95)
      Telegraph message from G. G. Evans is a photocopy
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, folder 735
    - E. & L. Merriam, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Elliott, E. B., 1866-69 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Ellsworth, William Wolcott, 1844-67, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 98-101)
      Letters to Ellsworth from Merriam Co. dated Mar 2 1846; Mar 14 1848; Apr 1 1852; Sep 19 1857; Apr 3, 5 and May 15, Oct 12, 1858 and Oct 31 1861 are later typed transcripts. Letter to W. C. Fowler dated Apr 6 1854 and letter to William G. Webster dated Sep 7 1854 are later typed transcripts
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, [1878] Aug 21 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Everett, Edward, 1856 Apr 23 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - "F" general, 1850-91 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Fields, James T., 1855, 1881 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Fish, Hamilton, 1850, 1875 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Fiske, Edward W., 1851 Mar 1 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Ford, Paul Leicester, [1901 Apr 1] (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Fowler, W. C., 1870-73 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Frelinghuysen, Frederick T., 1882 Feb 27 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - "G" general, 1859-90, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 111)
      Letter from J. G. Gilchrist and S.C. Griggs & Co. are photocopies
    - G. & C. Merriam, 1844-74, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 112-113)
      Letters dated Apr 3 1851, Sep 6 1859 and Nov 19 1859 are photocopies
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 717
    - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1873 Sep-Oct (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Garland, A. H., 1882 Feb 23 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - George Routledge & Sons, 1877 Mar (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Gilbert, R. R., 1854 Apr 13 (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Godkin, Edwin Lawrence, 1877 Dec 28 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Goodrich, Chauncey, 1844-50 (Box 9, Folder 119-123)
    - Goodrich, Chauncey, 1851-53 (Box 10, Folder 124-128)
      Letter to William W. Ellsworth dated Apr 2 1853 is a later typed transcript. Letter to Merriam Co. dated Nov 16 1853 is a later typed transcript
    - Goodrich, Chauncey, 1854-61, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 129-133)
    - Goodrich, William H., 1870 Dec 7 (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - Gorman, Willis Arnold, 1855 May 21 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Grant, Ulysses S., 1884 Aug 9 (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Greene, Richard Gleason, 1893 Sep 23 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Grout, Lewis, 1852 Mar 11 (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - "H" general, 1845-84, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 139-140)
      Letters from Daniel Harris, Joel Harris, L. A. Hopkins, Hudding & Brother, E. Hunt, and A. Huntington are photocopies
    - H.O. Houghton & Co., 1865-77 (Box 10, Folder 141-143)
    - H.O. Houghton & Co., 1878-91 (Box 11, Folder 144-147)
    - Hadley Brothers & Kane, 1873 Jul 26 (Box 11, Folder 148)
    - Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1841-68 (Box 11, Folder 149)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 718
    - Hall, C. C., 1856 Mar 3 (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - Halleck, Fitz-Greene, 1856 Mar (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - Hamlen, Benjamin L., 1844 Dec 13 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Harlan, John M., 1882 Feb 23 (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - Harper Brothers, 1853 Feb (Box 11, Folder 154)
    - Harris, William Torrey, 1880-89 (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1888 Dec 12 (Box 11, Folder 156)
      TLS to J. Q. Adams dated 1888 Dec 8. With forwarding letter by Adams, Putnam & Co.
    - Hayes, Rutherford B., 1880 Mar 3 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    - Henry, Joseph, 1856 Mar 17 (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1856 Oct 20 (Box 11, Folder 159)
    - Hoar, George Frisbie, 1891 Jan 13 (Box 11, Folder 160)
    - Holland, J. G., 1864 Sep 28 (Box 11, Folder 161)
    - Holley, Alexander Lyman, 1861 Feb-Oct (Box 11, Folder 162)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894, 1878-88 (Box 11, Folder 163)
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1859-60 (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - Houghton, Mifflin & Co., 1891-94 (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Howells, William Dean, 1878, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - Huntington, Francis Junius, 1853-62 (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - Imperial Dictionary, 1856-83 (Box 11, Folder 168)
    - Industries, Testimony of, 1868-79 (Box 11, Folder 169)
    - Infringement, 1879 Sep (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - Iowa, 1856-63 (Box 11, Folder 171)
    - Irving, Washington, 1849-51 (Box 11, Folder 172)
    - Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co., 1865-92 (Box 11, Folder 173-178)
    - "J" general, [1854] Dec 26 (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - J.B. Lippincott & Co., 1858-77 (Box 12, Folder 180)
    - J.S. & C. Adams, 1844-46 (Box 12, Folder 181)
    - James, John Angell, [1850] Dec 12 (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - James T. White & Co., 1879 Jul 25 (Box 12, Folder 183)
    - John Andrew & Son, 1861-73, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 184)
      Letters dated Oct 21, Oct 22, Dec 2, and Dec 18 1857 are photocopies
    - Johnson, Rossiter, 1878 Jan 23 (Box 12, Folder 185)
    - Jones, Henry, 1863-64, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 186)
    - Judson, Charles N., 1877-91 (Box 12, Folder 187)
    - "K" general, 1850, 1886 (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - Kansas, 1859 Mar 21 (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - Kimball, Horace E., 1860 Jun-Jul (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - Knox, Thomas Wallace, 1879 Jun 24 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - Kwong, Ki Chiu, 1879-81 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - "L" general, 1860 Aug 30 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - Lamar, L. Q. C., 1891 Feb 13 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Lane, John C., 1856 Mar 14 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Law Firms, Testimony of, 1879-80 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Le Grand & Geo. L. Marvin, 1852-56 (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Libraries, Testimony of, 1856, 1879 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Library of Congress, 1890-91 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Lincoln, Crawford, 1977 Dec (Box 12, Folder 200)
    - Lincoln, Robert Todd, 1882 Feb 6 (Box 12, Folder 201)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1864, 1878 (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Lord, Daniel, 1850 Jan 11 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1864 Sep 22 (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Lyman, C. S., 1861 Jan-Sep (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - "M" general, 1833-68, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 206)
      Letter from the Mercantile Library is a photocopy
    - Mackenzie, R. Shelton, 1864 Oct 3 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - Mahn, C. A. F., [1855]-58, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - Mann, Horace, 1848-50 (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - Marsh, George Perkins, 1856 Mar [12?] (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - Mason Brothers, 1856-66, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 211-212)
      Letters dated Sep 2, 10, 18 1857, and Feb 13 1866 are photocopies
    - Mason, Lowell, 1853-64 (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1856 Mar (Box 12, Folder 214)
    - Mayhew & Ivison, 1859 Sep (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - Merriam, A. F., 1848 Nov 3 (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Merriam, A. G., 1897-98 (Box 12, Folder 217)
    - Merriam, Charles, 1856-76, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 218)
      Letter dated Feb 9 1834 is a photocopy
    - Merriam, George, 1844-60, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 219)
      Letters dated Apr 1 1851, Jan 14 1852, Feb 22 1853, and Apr 9 1853 are photocopies
    - Merriam, George S., 1891 Oct 23 (Box 12, Folder 220)
    - Merriam, Homer, 1877-94 (Box 12, Folder 221)
    - Merriam, William, 1834 Oct 1 (Box 12, Folder 222)
    - Methodist Book Concern, 1880 Sep, Oct (Box 12, Folder 223)
    - Meyer, C., Secretary to H.R.H. Prince Albert, 1849 Jun 20 (Box 13, Folder 224)
    - Milton Bradley Co., 1891 Jun 6 (Box 13, Folder 225)
    - Minnesota, 1871 Sep (Box 13, Folder 226)
    - Mitchell, Donald Grant, 1856 Mar, Apr (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Mongkut, King of Siam, 1853-54 (Box 13, Folder 228)
    - Moody, Dwight Lyman, 1873 May 22 (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - "N" general, 1849-77 (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - Nesmith, T. A., 1854-68 (Box 13, Folder 231)
    - New York Tribune, 1881-89 (Box 13, Folder 232)
    - Notes, 1857, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 233)
      Letters dated Sep 29 1857, Oct 21 1857, Oct 27 1857, Nov 16 1857 are photocopies
    - "O" general, 1858-1950 (Box 13, Folder 234)
    - Ohio, 1856 Feb (Box 13, Folder 235)
    - "P" general, 1849-90 (Box 13, Folder 236)
    - Park, Edwards Amasa, 1858 Apr 15 (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - Pauncefote, Julian, Baron, 1891 Feb 21 (Box 13, Folder 238)
    - Peabody, Andrew P., 1854 Jan 12 (Box 13, Folder 239)
    - Pendleton, William S. (Box 13, Folder 240)
    - Pennsylvania, 1856 Mar 14 (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - Perkins, J. C., 1861-75 (Box 13, Folder 242)
    - Perkins, John, 1859 Mar 5 (Box 13, Folder 243)
      On verso is a letter from Savage & McCrea, dated 1859 Mar 5
    - Phelps, Austin, 1858 Apr (Box 13, Folder 244)
    - Phillips, Wendell, 1864 Jul 10 (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - Polk, James K. [autograph], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - Poole, William Frederick, 1855 Mar 7 (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - Porter, Noah, [1850]-89 (Box 13, Folder 248-252)
      Letter dated Apr 1859 encloses letter from C. A. F. Mahn. Letter dated Sep 26 1881 forwards letter from W. W. S. Keats
    - Printers & Printing, Testimony of, 1847-79 (Box 13, Folder 253)
    - Purcell, John Baptist, 1856 Sep (Box 13, Folder 254)
    - "R" general, 1854-79, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 255)
      Letter from F. & G.C. Rand is a photocopy
    - Reed, T. B., 1891 Jan 21 (Box 13, Folder 256)
    - Regan, Bishop, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 257)
    - Rice, Kendall & Co., 1865 Mar 15 (Box 13, Folder 258)
    - Rowley, H. Curtis, 1890 Feb 17 (Box 13, Folder 259)
    - "S" general, 1848-1908, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 260)
      Letters from George W. Seavy and W. Stowe are photocopies
    - Sargent, Epes, 1856-59, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 261)
      Letter dated Nov 18 1857 is a photocopy
    - Saxe, John Godfrey, 1856 Mar 20 (Box 13, Folder 262)
    - Schools and Colleges, Testimonials of, 1848-92 (Box 14, Folder 263-267)
    - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1889 Jun 7 (Box 14, Folder 268)
    - Seelye, Julius Hawley, 1880 Mar 17 (Box 14, Folder 269)
    - Seward, William Henry, 1856 Mar (Box 14, Folder 270)
    - Shearman, Francis W., 1851-55 (Box 14, Folder 271)
    - Shears, A. G., 1863 Mar 16 (Box 14, Folder 272)
    - Sheldon, E. S., 1889 Mar-Sep (Box 14, Folder 273)
      Letter dated Apr 3 1889 written on second page of letter from Noah Porter to Merriam & Co. dated Mar 31 1889
    - Sherman, William T., 1875 Nov 12 (Box 14, Folder 274)
    - Sickels, David Banks, 1880-88 (Box 14, Folder 275)
    - Skeat, W. W., 1881 Jul, Oct (Box 14, Folder 276)
    - Spackman, William M., 1895-96 (Box 14, Folder 277)
    - Sparks, Jared, 1848 Apr 20 (Box 14, Folder 278)
    - Spencer, John C., 1851 Jun 18 (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Stebbins, C. B., 1859-62 (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Stowe, C. E., 1864-65 (Box 14, Folder 281)
    - Straw, Levi H., 1860-62 (Box 14, Folder 282)
    - Sumner, Charles, 1856 Mar 12 (Box 14, Folder 283)
    - Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, 1889-91 (Box 14, Folder 284)
    - Supreme Court of Iowa, 1856 Jun 10 (Box 14, Folder 285)
    - Supreme Court of Kansas, 1890-91 (Box 14, Folder 286)
    - Supreme Court of South Dakota, 1890 Feb-Mar (Box 14, Folder 287)
    - Swan, Brewer & Tileston, 1860 Oct 15 (Box 14, Folder 288)
    - Swan, Brown & Tileston, 1861 Jan 25 (Box 14, Folder 289)
    - "T" general, 1850-89, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 290)
      Letter from Tillman C. Trowbridge is a photocopy
    - Taylor, Bayard, 1856 Mar 26 (Box 14, Folder 291)
    - Taylor, Zachary, 1849 May 26 (Box 14, Folder 292)
    - Terhune, John, 1858 Jan-Feb (Box 14, Folder 293)
    - Thomas, Isaiah, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 294)
      Letter from Ebenezer Andrews dated Aug 9 1804 is a photocopy
    - Thomas, Joseph, 1861 Jan-Oct (Box 14, Folder 295)
    - Ticknor, George, 1864 Oct 1 (Box 14, Folder 296)
    - Tilton, D., 1866 Feb-Apr (Box 14, Folder 297)
    - Trübner & Co., 1860 Jun 8 (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - Tyler, Moses Coit, 1884 Jan 25 (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - Tyler, W. S., 1851 Dec 22 (Box 14, Folder 300)
    - United Kingdom of Sweden and Norway, 1858 Feb 2 (Box 14, Folder 301)
    - United States Government Officials, Testimonials of, 1850-90 (Box 14, Folder 302)
    - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1848 Dec (Box 14, Folder 303)
    - "W" general, 1849-1927 (Box 14, Folder 304)
    - Walker, Amasa, 1850 Jan 19 (Box 14, Folder 305)
    - Walker, Francis Amasa, 1875 Jun 29 (Box 14, Folder 306)
    - Wanamaker, John, 1889 Jul 1 (Box 14, Folder 307)
    - Washington, Booker T., 1887 May 21 (Box 14, Folder 308)
    - Webster, Daniel, 1848 Mar 21 (Box 14, Folder 309)
    - Webster, Noah, 1831, 1834, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 310-311)
      Letter dated Feb 16 1831 to his wife Letter dated Mar 6 1834 to N. & J. White. Typed transcripts only for the following letters: Jun 2 1797, Feb 12 1803, Feb 19 1856, Jan 21 1857. Letters dated Sep 26 1815, Dec 14 1834, Feb 3 1835, Mar 3 1837, and Jan 14 1857 are photocopies
    - Webster, William G., 1847-66 (Box 15, Folder 312-315)
      Letter dated Apr 12 1853 is a later typed transcript
    - Webster Heirs, 1861-70 (Box 15, Folder 316)
    - Webster's Dictionary
      - Royal Octavo Edition, 1867 Feb 26 (Box 15, Folder 317)
      - Webster's Academic Dictionary, 1856 Feb 20 (Box 15, Folder 318)
      - Explanatory & Pronuncing English Dictionary, with Synonyms, 1857, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 319)
      - Suggested Corrections and Additions
        - Correspondence, 1861-65 (Box 15, Folder 320-321)
        - Correspondence, 1866-67 (Box 15, Folder 322-325)
        - Correspondence, 1868-69 (Box 15, Folder 326-329)
        - Correspondence, 1870-71 (Box 16, Folder 330-333)
        - Correspondence, 1872 (Box 16, Folder 334-335)
        - Correspondence, 1873 (Box 16, Folder 336-339)
        - Correspondence, 1874 (Box 16, Folder 340-343)
        - Correspondence, 1876 Feb 4 (Box 17, Folder 344)
        - Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 345)
      - Webster's in Southern U.S., 1856 Apr 9 (Box 17, Folder 346)
    - Wells, David Ames, 1856 Mar 24 (Box 17, Folder 347)
    - Wells, W. H., 1856-79 (Box 17, Folder 348)
    - Wheeler, William Adolphus
      - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 17, Folder 349)
      - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 17, Folder 350-355)
      - Correspondence, 1862 Jan-Jun (Box 17, Folder 356-361)
      - Correspondence, 1862 Jul-Sep (Box 18, Folder 362-367)
      - Correspondence, 1862 Oct-Dec (Box 18, Folder 368-369)
      - Correspondence, 1863 (Box 18, Folder 370-371)
      - Correspondence, 1864 (Box 18, Folder 372-374)
      - Correspondence, 1865-66 (Box 18, Folder 375-376)
      - Correspondence, 1867-68 (Box 19, Folder 377-379)
      - Correspondence, 1869 (Box 19, Folder 380-381)
      - Correspondence, 1870-71 (Box 19, Folder 382-384)
      - Correspondence, 1872 (Box 19, Folder 385-387)
      - Correspondence, 1873 Jan-May (Box 19, Folder 388-390)
      - Correspondence, 1873 Jun-Dec (Box 20, Folder 391-393)
      - Correspondence, 1874 (Box 20, Folder 394-395)
      - Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 396)
      - Covers of volumes with Wheeler correspondence previously tipped in
    - White, Andrew Dickson, 1884 Jan 14 (Box 20, Folder 397)
      Appended testimonials signed by Hiram Corson, W. D. Wilson, T. F. Crane, G. Harris, and H. S. White, professors at Cornell University
    - White, Henry, 1839-71 (Box 20, Folder 398)
    - White, Norman, 1851-58, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 399)
      Letters dated Apr 7, 11, 12, and 13 1854 are photocopies
    - White & Sheffield, 1844-46 (Box 20, Folder 400)
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1878-91 (Box 20, Folder 401)
    - Wiley, Calvin Henderson, 1860 Mar 9 (Box 20, Folder 402)
    - Wiley, John, 1863 Apr (Box 20, Folder 403)
    - Wilkins, Carter & Co., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 404)
    - Willard, Frances Elizabeth, 1890 May 21 (Box 20, Folder 405)
    - Willis, Nathaniel Parker, 1856 Mar 26 (Box 20, Folder 406)
    - Wisconsin, 1859-78, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 407)
      Letter dated Apr 21 1857 is a photocopy
    - Wood, J. G., 1884 Dec 16 (Box 20, Folder 408)
    - Worcester's Dictionary, 1855-78 (Box 20, Folder 409)
  - DOCUMENTS AND OTHER PAPERS
    - "A" general, 1883 (Box 20, Folder 410)
    - A.L. Bancroft & Co., 1884 Jul 25 (Box 20, Folder 411)
    - A.S. Barnes & Co., 1855 Dec 5 (Box 20, Folder 412)
    - Abridgments, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 413)
      Indenture dated Apr 7 1854 is a later typed transcript
    - Allen, William, 1855 (Box 20, Folder 414)
    - An American Dictionary, etc. - 1847, 1844-60 (Box 20, Folder 415)
      Document dated Dec 1851 is a later typed transcript
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, folder 736
    - An American Dictionary, etc. - 1859, 1855-59 (Box 20, Folder 416)
    - An American Dictionary, etc. - 1864, 1861-64 (Box 20, Folder 417)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, folder 737
    - Ashmun, George, 1845 Jun 4 (Box 20, Folder 418)
    - Award of Arbitrators, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 419)
      Document is a later typed transcript
    - "B" general, 1856-60, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 420)
    - Baltimore, Maryland Public Schools (Box 20, Folder 421)
    - Bell & Daldy, 1866-73 (Box 20, Folder 422)
    - Blackie & Son, 1856-59, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 423)
    - Bogue, David, 1850 Nov 22 (Box 20, Folder 424)
    - Booksellers, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 425)
      Document is a photocopy
    - Boston Stereotype Foundry, 1862-64 (Box 21, Folder 426)
    - Boston Type & Stereo Foundry, 1847 Mar-Oct (Box 21, Folder 427)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 719
    - "C" general, 1856-73, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 428)
      Statement of account from Sumner Chapin is a photocopy. Document concerning commutation is a later typed transcript
    - Campbell, L. J., 1877-78 (Box 21, Folder 429)
    - Case, Lockwood & Co., 1860, 1873 (Box 21, Folder 430)
    - Case, Tiffany & Co., 1852-56 (Box 21, Folder 431-432)
    - Cathcart, George R., 1892 Jul 2 (Box 21, Folder 433)
    - Chapman, R. A., [1853 Apr 11] (Box 21, Folder 434)
    - Chapman & Morris, [1853 Apr 1] (Box 21, Folder 435)
    - Choate, Rufus, 1854 Jan (Box 21, Folder 436)
    - Co-Partnership Agreements, 1840-87 (Box 21, Folder 437)
    - Curtis, Benjamin Robbins, 1860-64 (Box 21, Folder 438)
    - "D" general, 1848 Jul 4 (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - D. Appleton & Co., 1856-86 (Box 21, Folder 440-441)
    - D.H. Tripp & Co., 1865-68 (Box 21, Folder 442)
    - Deeds, 1847-59 (Box 21, Folder 443)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 720
    - Denison, Charles H., 1882-83 (Box 21, Folder 444)
    - Electrotyping, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 445)
    - Elementary Spelling Book, 1844-1908 (Box 21, Folder 446)
    - Ellsworth, William Wolcott, 1844, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 447)
      Documents dated 1857-59 are later typed transcripts
    - Executors of Noah Webster, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 448)
    - F.J. Huntington & Co., 1837 Mar 30 (Box 21, Folder 449)
    - F.S. & J. Parker, 1847 Mar 10 (Box 21, Folder 450)
    - Fowler, W. C., 1854-55 (Box 21, Folder 451)
    - "G" general, [1875 Jul] (Box 21, Folder 452)
    - G. &. C. Merriam, 1832-1909, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 453-457)
      Documents dated 1834-82 and undated are photocopies
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 721
    - Goodrich, Chauncey, 1845-65, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 458-460)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 722
    - "H" general, 1848-63 (Box 22, Folder 461)
    - H. O. Houghton & Co., 1863-82 (Box 22, Folder 462-464)
    - Huntington, Francis Junius, 1853-57, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 465)
      Documents dated Apr 1 1854 and Apr 3 1857 later typed transcripts
    - Huntington & Savage, 1831-54, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 466)
    - Imperial Dictionary, 1883 Apr
    - Indiana, 1855 Nov 28 (Box 22, Folder 467)
    - Iowa, 1858-62 (Box 22, Folder 468)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 724
    - Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co., 1866-90 (Box 23, Folder 469-470)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 725
    - J.B. Lippincott & Co., 1856-77, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 471-472)
    - J.S. & C. Adams, 1843-44 (Box 23, Folder 473)
    - John Andrew & Son, 1861, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 474)
    - Jones, Henry, 1847 Jan-Oct (Box 23, Folder 475)
    - Judson, Charles N., 1877 Nov (Box 23, Folder 476)
    - Kwong, Ki Chiu, 1870-80 (Box 23, Folder 477)
    - "L" general, 1885 Jun 9 (Box 23, Folder 478)
    - Library of Congress, 1847-90 (Box 23, Folder 479)
    - Little, Benjamin, 1832-38 (Box 23, Folder 480)
    - Lord, Daniel, 1853 Oct-Nov (Box 23, Folder 481)
    - "M" general, 1863-95 (Box 23, Folder 482)
    - Mahn, C. A. F., 1855-62 (Box 23, Folder 483)
    - Mason Brothers, 1854-67, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 484-485)
    - Mason, Lowell, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 486)
    - Merriam, Charles, 1877-80 (Box 23, Folder 487)
    - Merriam, George, 1824 Apr 5 (Box 23, Folder 488)
    - Merriam, Homer, 1856-89 (Box 23, Folder 489)
    - Merriam, Chapin & Co., 1853-55, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 490)
      Documents dated 1850-51 are photocopies, as is the calendar for 1856
    - Michigan, 1857, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 491)
    - Minnesota, [1871], 1883 (Box 23, Folder 492)
    - Mitchell, J. B., 1873-76 (Box 24, Folder 493)
    - "N" general, 1862 Jul 23 (Box 24, Folder 494)
    - Nesmith, T. A., [1868] (Box 24, Folder 495)
    - New York, 1850-56 (Box 24, Folder 496)
    - North Carolina, 1856 Apr 14 (Box 24, Folder 497)
    - Notes, 1844-73 (Box 24, Folder 498)
    - "P" general, 1879, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 499)
      Document signed by Willis Phelps is a photocopy
    - Parker, Joseph, 1886 Mar 8 (Box 24, Folder 500)
    - Perkins, John, 1851 Aug 1 (Box 24, Folder 501)
    - Porter, Noah, 1855-79 (Box 24, Folder 502)
    - "R" general, 1850-66, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 503)
      Document signed by William J. Rhees is a photocopy
    - Renewers, 1856, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 504)
      Documents dated May 12 1854 and Apr 14 1857 are later typed transcripts
    - Rowley, H. Curtis, [1889] (Box 24, Folder 505)
    - Russell, W. F., 1870-75 (Box 24, Folder 506)
    - "S" general, 1834-72 (Box 24, Folder 507)
    - Sales, [1864-65] (Box 24, Folder 508)
    - Samuel Bowles & Company, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 509)
      Documents are photocopies
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 726
    - Schaff, Philip, 1865 Apr (Box 24, Folder 510)
    - Schools and Colleges, Testimonials of, 1848-1901 (Box 24, Folder 511)
    - Smithsonian Institution, 1847 Dec 22 (Box 24, Folder 512)
    - Sobieski, ----, 1857 (Box 24, Folder 513)
    - Springfield Fire & Insurance Company, 1864, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 514)
      Document dated Sep 26 1854 is a photocopy
    - Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, 1882-90 (Box 24, Folder 515)
    - Supreme Court of Iowa, 1881 Aug 20 (Box 24, Folder 516)
    - Supreme Court of Nebraska, [1881 Oct 1] (Box 24, Folder 517)